Wilton Historical Society Genealogy Collection
Wilton History Room, Wilton Historical Society
Wilton Historical Society Genealogy Collection
circa 1700-present
1900s
Wilton Historical Society (Wilton, Conn.)
GEN
17 linear feet / 4 drawers, 14 binders, 2 tubes
Wilton History Room, Wilton Historical Society
The Wilton Historical Society Genealogy Collection contains genealogical information in the form of notes, family trees, obituaries, newspaper clippings, and other documents pertaining to early Wilton families. The bulk of the collection is from the 1900s.
Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
The bulk of the Wilton Historical Society Genealogy Collection has been donated by individuals and families. Portions have been compiled by members of the Wilton Historical Society.
History
1. Wilton Historical Society Genealogy Collection
The Wilton Historical Society, founded in 1938, collected extensive genealogical materials pertaining to early Wilton families. Additions have been made by Carol Russell, Wilton Historical Society Archivist and Wilton Town Historian. The majority of the material included in the collection was created by family members. Genealogical research by local historians G. Evans Hubbard, David Hermon Van Hoosear, and Robert Russell is also included in, or frequently used in conjunction with, this collection.
2. Wilton History Room
The Wilton History Room is a unique collaboration between the Wilton Historical Society (WHS) and the Wilton Library Association (WLA). Compiled beginning in 1938, the archival collections of the Wilton Historical Society had been stored in the 18th century Fitch House. In 1980, the officers and trustees of the WHS, in conversation with the director and board members of the WLA, determined that a climate controlled space, improved organization, and better public accessibility were necessary; and so in January 1984 they established a home for the collection in the Wilton Library. Organization of the collections was supported by the Cudlipp Memorial Fund and undertaken by Carol Russell. The Wilton Historical Society has retained its ownership, while the Wilton Library maintains the collections, and provides access and assistance to patrons.
The Wilton History Room is one of the most complete, organized, and well-staffed historical research facilities, for a town of our size, in Fairfield County. It is supported by the WHS, the WLA, The Russell Fund, The History Room Fund, local non-profit organizations, individual donors, and community volunteers.
Today, the original archival collections of the WHS take up half of the Wilton History Room. Another quarter are library items. The collected papers of local organizations comprise the remainder: Cannon Grange, Children's Theater, Daughters of the American Revolution, Hurlbutt Street School House Association, Kiwanis Club, League of Women Voters, Rotary Club, Town Association, Weir Farm Stewardship Committee, Wilton Garden Club, Wilton Land Conservation Trust, Wilton Library, Wilton Playshop, Wilton Woman's Club, and more.
Scope and Content of Collection
The information available for families and individual family members varies widely. For families, the information may include family trees and notes on genealogy and family history. For individual family members, the information may include significant dates and life events, occupation, place of residence, obituaries, burial location, and miscellaneous biographical notes.
Family names in the collection include: Abbott, Adams, Albin, Allen, Ambler, Andrews, Arnold, Avery, Banks, Barber, Barbour, Barlow, Barmore, Barnes, Bassett, Batterson, Beale, Bedient, Beers, Belden, Benedict, Bennett, Bethel, Betts, Birchard (Burchard), Bishop, Bixby, Boardman, Boas, Borglum, Bouton, Boyd, Bradley, Britto, Brown, Budd, Burchard, Burling, Burlock, Burr, Burwell, Bush, Butler, Buttery, Byington, Canfield, Cannon, Card, Carter, Chandler, Chapman, Chard, Chelminski, Chichester, Church, Clark, Cole, Coley, Collier, Comstock, Copp, Couch, Crawford, Davenport, Davis, Dayton, DeForest, Desloge, Disbrow, Downs, Dunning, Eakland, Easton, Eckert, Edwards, Elmer, Ferris, Fillow, Fisher, Fitch, Fontayne (Fountain), Foote, Foster, Fox, Fuller, Gates, Gaylord, Gibbs, Gilbert, Godfrey, Gorham, Grannis, Gray, Green, Gregory, Grey, Grumman, Guire (Guyer), Gunning, Hale, Hanford, Hart, Hawley, Hendrick, Hickok (Hickox), Hodge (Hodges), Holmes, Hottlelet, Howes, Hoyt, Hubbard, Hubbell, Hull, Huntington, Hurd, Hurlbutt (Hurlburt), Hyatt, Jackson, Jellif, Jennings, Jessup, Jones, Keeler, Keiser, Kellogg, Kelsey, Kent, Ketchum, Kimberly, Knapp, Lawrence, Lewis, Lobdell, Lockwood, Long, Lyon, Manning, Marhoffer, Marvin, Marvin, Mead, Merchant, Meridenhall, Merwin, Meyer, Middlebrook, Miller, Montgomery, Morehouse, Morgan, Nash, Nichols, Ogden, Olmstead, Osborn, Ottavi, Pardee (Purdee), Partrick, Patchen, Phillips, Pierce (Pearce), Platt, Pont, Post, Price, Randal (Randle, Randall), Raymond, Reed, Resseguie, Richards, Rockwell, Rogers, Rounds, Rusco (Ruscoe), Sackman, Samuelson, Sanford, Saunders, Schenck, Schilcher, Schlichting, Schmitt, Scofield, Scott, Scribner, Searles, Seeley, Selleck, Seymour, Sherman, Sherwood, Shipman, Slawson (Slason, Slosson), Sloan, Sloat, Smith, Spencer, Squire, St. John, Sterling, Stetson, Stewart, Stivers, Stratton, Street, Stuart, Sturges, Sudlow, Taylor, Terrill, Thompson, Tito, Treadwell, Trowbridge, Van Hoosear, Van Horn (Van Horne), Wakeman, Walker, Waterhouse (Watrous), Weed, Weir, Welton, West, Weston, Whitlock, Whitney, Willard, Williams, Wilson, Wirth, Wood (Woods), Woodward, Young, and Youngquist.
Arrangement
The collection is in folders arranged alphabetically by family name.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Biography.; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.).; Correspondence.; Genealogy.; Obituaries.
Related Collections
Researchers should also search for content organized by family names and historical locations of residence in the Wilton History Room's other collections, particularly Manuscripts, Neighborhoods, and Maps, and in G. Evans Hubbard's Wilton Families and Supplement to Wilton Families, consisting of seven binders of the author's genealogical research. The history of select Wilton families and individuals is also narrated in Robert Russell's Wilton, Connecticut: Three Centuries of People, Places, and Progress. The History Room has bound genealogies relating to Wilton family names as well. These are searchable online through the Wilton Library Catalog. Finally, the Card File is helpful in locating specific family names mentioned in the early division of Wilton lands and the Norwalk Land Records.
Separated Material
Select family artifacts are housed at the Wilton Historical Society Museum.
- Series 1. Family names
  - A - C
    - Abbott family, undated; Covers the years 1672-1941. Files 102b and 102c include David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes and book excerpt. (Box 5, Folder 102a, 102aa, 102ab, 102b, 102c)
    - Adams family, undated (Box 5, Folder 103a)
    - Albin family, undated (Box 5, Folder 103b)
    - Allen family, undated (Box 5, Folder 103c)
    - Ambler family, undated; See also Diaries, Scrapbooks, PHO. (Box 5, Folder 103d)
    - Andrews family, undated; Covers the years 1630-1687, and 1711-1827. Files 104b and 104c include David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes and book excerpt. (Box 5, Folder 104a, 104b, 104c)
    - Arnold family, undated; Covers the years 1690-1941. See also Arnold Genealogy Chart in Map Tube #1. (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Avery family, undated; Covers the years 1832-1895. (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - Banks family, undated (Box 5, Folder 112b)
    - Barber family, undated; Files include David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes and book excerpt. (Box 5, Folder 113a, 113b)
    - Barbour family, undated (Box 5, Folder 113c)
    - Barlow, Joel, 1754-1812, undated (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - Barmore family, undated; Covers the years 1702-1831. (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - Barnes family, undated (Box 5, Folder 117a)
    - Bassett family, undated (Box 5, Folder 117b)
    - Batterson family, undated; Covers the years 1700-1897. (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Beale family, undated; Covers the years 1748-1845. (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - Bedient family, undated; Covers the years 1600-1947. Files 125b through 125g include David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes and book excerpt. (Box 5, Folder 121, 122, 123, 125b, 125c, 125d, 125e, 125f, 125g)
    - Bedient family - Correspondence, 1922-1969 (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - Bedient family - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 5, Folder 125a)
    - Beers family, undated; Covers the years 1625-1870. File 126a contains the family newsletter. (Box 5, Folder 126a, 126b, 127a)
    - Beers family in the Biographical Record of Fairfield County and Index to Wilton Names, undated (Box 5, Folder 127b)
    - Belden family, undated; Bulk of the material dates to the years 1671-1974. File 130c includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes. See also GEN, Fitch, and Map Tube #1. (Box 5, Folder 128, 129, 130a, 130b, 130c)
    - Benedict family, undated; Covers the years 1617-1898. (Box 5, Folder 131)
    - Bennett family, undated; Covers the years 1616-1976. (Box 5, Folder 133)
    - Bethel family, undated (Box 5, Folder 134)
    - Betts family, undated; Bulk of File 135 relates to the years 1505-1926. Bulk of File 137 relates to the years 1803-1975. (Box 5, Folder 135, 137)
    - Betts, Greg, undated; Includes correspondence and index to Thomas Betts and His Descendants by C. Wyllys Betts, located in Books 929.2 Betts. (Box 19, Folder 136)
    - Betts, Stephen, undated (Box 5, Folder 138)
    - Birchard family, undated; Covers the years 1663-1795. (Box 5, Folder 139)
    - Bishop family, undated; Covers the years 1639-1892. (Box 5, Folder 141)
    - Bixby family, undated (Box 5, Folder 142a, 142b, 142c, 142d, 142e, 142f, 142g, 142h, 142i, 142j)
    - Boardman family, undated (Box 5, Folder 143a)
    - Boas family, undated (Box 5, Folder 143aa)
    - Borglum family, undated (Box 5, Folder 143ab)
    - Bouton family, undated; Covers the years 1656-1725. (Box 5, Folder 143b)
    - Boyd family, undated (Box 5, Folder 143c)
    - Bradley family, undated; Files include David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes and book excerpt. (Box 5, Folder 144a, 144b)
    - Bradley, Flora, undated; See also Flora Bradley's postcard collection, in a box on Black Shelf 20. (Box 5, Folder 144c)
    - Britto family, undated (Box 5, Folder 144d)
    - Brown family, undated; Covers the years 1682-1903. (Box 5, Folder 145)
    - Budd family, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 147a)
    - Burchard family, undated (Box 5, Folder 147b)
    - Burling family, undated (Box 5, Folder 148a)
    - Burlock family, undated (Box 5, Folder 148b)
    - Burr family, undated; Covers the years 1700-1900. (Box 5, Folder 149a)
    - Burwell family, undated (Box 5, Folder 151a)
    - Bush family, undated (Box 5, Folder 149b)
    - Butler family, undated (Box 5, Folder 149c)
    - Buttery family, undated (Box 5, Folder 150)
    - Byington family, undated; Covers the years 1738-1897. (Box 5, Folder 151b)
    - Canfield family, undated; Includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's and G. Evans Hubbard's notes. (Box 5, Folder 153)
    - Cannon family, undated (Box 5, Folder 155a)
    - Card family, undated (Box 5, Folder 155b)
    - Carter family, undated (Box 5, Folder 155c)
    - Chandler family, undated; Covers the years 1827-1913. (Box 5, Folder 156)
    - Chapman family, undated; Covers the years 1616-1936. (Box 5, Folder 158a)
    - Chard family, undated (Box 5, Folder 158b)
    - Chelminski family, undated (Box 5, Folder 158c)
    - Chichester family, undated (Box 5, Folder 159)
    - Church family, undated; Covers the years 1610-1896. (Box 5, Folder 160)
    - Clark family, undated (Box 5, Folder 161)
    - Cole family, undated; Covers the years 1678-1957. File 162b includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes. (Box 5, Folder 162a, 162ab, 162b)
    - Coley family, undated; File 162d includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes. (Box 5, Folder 162c, 162d)
    - Collier family, undated (Box 5, Folder 163a)
    - Comstock family, undated; Materials trace the family back to 1595. Files 164b and 164c include David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes and book excerpt. (Box 5, Folder 164a, 164b, 164c)
    - Copp, Dr. John, undated (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - Couch family, undated; Includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes. (Box 5, Folder 168)
    - Crawford family, undated; Includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes. (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - Miscellaneous "A's", undated (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Miscellaneous "B's", undated (Box 5, Folder 112a)
    - Miscellaneous "C's", undated (Box 5, Folder 152)
  - D - H
    - Davenport family, undated (Box 5, Folder 170a)
    - Davis family, undated; Covers the years 1597-1913. See also GEN, Abbott. (Box 5, Folder 170b)
    - Dayton family, undated (Box 5, Folder 171)
    - DeForest family, undated; Covers the years 1616-1823. See also card file in grey box on Black Case 20. (Box 5, Folder 172a)
    - Desloge family, undated (Box 5, Folder 172b, 172c)
    - Disbrow family, undated (Box 5, Folder 173a)
    - Downs family, undated; Includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes. (Box 5, Folder 173b)
    - Dunning family, undated; Covers the years 1700-1900. File 176 includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes. (Box 5, Folder 174, 175, 176)
    - Eakland family, undated (Box 5, Folder 181a)
    - Easton family, undated (Box 5, Folder 181aa)
    - Eckert family, undated (Box 5, Folder 181aaa)
    - Edwards family, undated (Box 5, Folder 181b)
    - Elmer family, undated (Box 5, Folder 182)
    - Ferris family, undated (Box 5, Folder 185b)
    - Fillow family, undated; File 186s includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's Copy of "Fillow Genealogy" with his notes. File 186b contains an addendum to "Fillow Genealogy." (Box 5, Folder 186a, 186b, 186c)
    - Fisher family, undated; Covers the years 1636-1830. (Box 5, Folder 188)
    - Fitch family, undated; File 193b includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes. See also GEN, Belden and Sturges. See also Fitch-Sturges Ancestral Register (MC 7-8), and Map Tube #1. (Box 5, Folder 189, 190, 191, 192, 193a, 193c, 193b)
    - Fitch, Rosemary - Correspondence on genealogy, undated; See also GEN, Belden and Sturges. See also Fitch-Sturges Ancestral Register (MC 7-8), and Map Tube #1. (Box 5, Folder 193f)
    - Fitch, Rosemary - Writings on Arthur Treat Fitch, undated; See also GEN, Belden and Sturges. See also Fitch-Sturges Ancestral Register (MC 7-8), and Map Tube #1. (Box 5, Folder 193e)
    - Fitch, Sarah A., undated; See also GEN, Belden and Sturges. See also Fitch-Sturges Ancestral Register (MC 7-8), and Map Tube #1. (Box 5, Folder 193d)
    - Fontayne / Fountain family, undated; Covers the years 1633-1878. (Box 5, Folder 194)
    - Foote family, undated (Box 5, Folder 195a)
    - Foster family, undated (Box 5, Folder 195b)
    - Fox family, undated (Box 5, Folder 195c)
    - Fuller family, undated (Box 5, Folder 195d)
    - Gates family, undated (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - Gaylord family, undated; Covers the years 1598-1859. (Box 5, Folder 198)
    - Gibbs family, undated; Covers the years 1680-1835. (Box 5, Folder 202)
    - Gilbert family, undated; Covers the years 1670-1874. (Box 5, Folder 204a)
    - Godfrey family, undated (Box 5, Folder 204b)
    - Gorham family, undated; See also Genealogical Chart, Map Tube #14. (Box 5, Folder 205a)
    - Grannis family, undated; Includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes. (Box 5, Folder 205b)
    - Gray family, undated; Includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes. (Box 5, Folder 205c)
    - Green family, undated (Box 5, Folder 205d)
    - Gregory family, undated; Includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes in File 209d, genealogical notes by Ginny Gregory in File 209e, and 1913 genealogy by Marian Olmstead in File 207b. (Box 5, Folder 206a, 206ab, 207b, 209d, 209e)
    - Gregory family - Migrations, undated (Box 5, Folder 209c)
    - Gregory, Charles, undated (Box 5, Folder 206b)
    - Gregory, Helen - Papers, undated; Includes her papers. (Box 5, Folder 207a)
    - Gregory, Henry, undated (Box 5, Folder 208a)
    - Gregory, John, undated (Box 5, Folder 208b)
    - Gregory, Julian Sr. and Julian Gregory, Jr., undated (Box 5, Folder 208c)
    - Gregory, Lewis, undated; Includes material from Helen Gregory's "Gregory Family History." (Box 5, Folder 209a, 209b)
    - Grey family, undated (Box 5, Folder 210)
    - Grumman family, undated; Files 221, 222, and 223 include David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes. File 224 includes notes by Virginia Bepler. (Box 5, Folder 220, 221, 222, 223, 224)
    - Guire / Guyer family, undated (Box 5, Folder 228)
    - Gunning family, undated (Box 5, Folder 230)
    - Hale family, undated; Covers the years 1770-1828. (Box 5, Folder 251, 252, 253, 254, 255, 256)
    - Hanford family, undated; Covers the years 1752-1805. (Box 5, Folder 257a)
    - Hart family, undated (Box 5, Folder 257b)
    - Hawley family, undated (Box 5, Folder 257c)
    - Hendrick family, undated (Box 5, Folder 258a)
    - Hickok / Hickox family, undated; Covers the years 1643-1931. (Box 5, Folder 258b)
    - Hodge / Hodges family, undated; Covers the years 1750-1830. (Box 5, Folder 258c)
    - Holmes family, undated (Box 5, Folder 259a)
    - Hottlelet family, undated (Box 5, Folder 259aa)
    - Howes family, undated (Box 5, Folder 259b)
    - Hoyt family, undated; Covers the years 1590-1867. (Box 5, Folder 260)
    - Hubbard family, undated (Box 5, Folder 263)
    - Hubbard family - Correspondence on genealogical research, 1937-1948 (Box 5, Folder 264)
    - Hubbell family, undated; Covers the years 1802-1879. (Box 5, Folder 268)
    - Hull family, undated (Box 5, Folder 270a)
    - Huntington family, undated (Box 5, Folder 270b)
    - Hurd family, undated; Covers the years 1764-1902. (Box 5, Folder 271a)
    - Hurlbutt family, undated; Covers the years 1610-1912. File 272b includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes. (Box 5, Folder 271b, 272a, 272b)
    - Hyatt family, undated; Covers the years 1633-1873. (Box 5, Folder 273)
    - Miscellaneous "D's", undated (Box 5, Folder 169)
    - Miscellaneous "E's", undated (Box 5, Folder 180)
    - Miscellaneous "F's", undated (Box 5, Folder 185a)
    - Miscellaneous "G's", undated (Box 5, Folder 196)
    - Miscellaneous "H's", undated (Box 5, Folder 250a)
  - I - R
    - Jackson family, undated; Covers the years 1648-1895. See also WHI, Farms, Jackson. (Box 5, Folder 276)
    - Jellif family, undated (Box 5, Folder 277a)
    - Jennings family, undated (Box 5, Folder 277b)
    - Jessup family, undated (Box 5, Folder 278)
    - Jones family, undated; Covers the years 1820-1892. (Box 5, Folder 280)
    - Keeler family, undated; Covers the years 1613-1933. See also WHI, PM, Notices, Auction. (Box 5, Folder 302a)
    - Keiser family, undated (Box 5, Folder 302b)
    - Kellogg family, undated (Box 5, Folder 303a)
    - Kelsey family, undated; Covers the years 1745-1821. (Box 5, Folder 303b)
    - Kent family, undated; Covers the years 1590-1710. (Box 5, Folder 304)
    - Ketchum family, undated; Covers the years 1615-1796 and 1944-1949. (Box 5, Folder 306)
    - Kimberly family, undated (Box 5, Folder 307)
    - Knapp family, undated; Covers the years 1540-1923. (Box 5, Folder 308)
    - Lawrence family, undated; Covers the years 1708-1794. (Box 5, Folder 314)
    - Lewis family, undated (Box 5, Folder 315a)
    - Lobdell family, undated (Box 5, Folder 315b)
    - Lockwood family, undated (Box 5, Folder 316)
    - Long family, undated (Box 5, Folder 317)
    - Lyon family, undated (Box 5, Folder 318)
    - Manning family, undated; See also WHI, PM, Manning. (Box 5, Folder 321a)
    - Marhoffer family, undated (Box 5, Folder 321b)
    - Marvin family, undated; File 322 covers the years 1635-1806. File 324 covers the years 1639-1897. (Box 5, Folder 322, 324)
    - Marvin family - Correspondence, 1886-1898 (Box 5, Folder 326)
    - Mead family, undated; Covers the years 1700-1816. (Box 5, Folder 330)
    - Merchant family, undated (Box 5, Folder 332)
    - Meridenhall family, undated (Box 5, Folder 331)
    - Merwin family, undated (Box 5, Folder 333a)
    - Merwin, Rev. Samuel J., undated; See also Ledger #123. (Box 5, Folder 333b)
    - Meyer family, undated (Box 5, Folder 333c)
    - Middlebrook family, undated; Covers the years 1600-1851. (Box 5, Folder 334, 336)
    - Miller family, undated (Box 5, Folder 338)
    - Miscellaneous "I's", undated (Box 5, Folder 274)
    - Miscellaneous "J's", undated (Box 5, Folder 275)
    - Miscellaneous "K's", undated (Box 5, Folder 295)
    - Miscellaneous "L's", undated (Box 5, Folder 312)
    - Miscellaneous "M's", undated (Box 5, Folder 320)
    - Miscellaneous "N's", undated (Box 5, Folder 346)
    - Miscellaneous "O's", undated (Box 5, Folder 349)
    - Miscellaneous "P's", undated (Box 5, Folder 400)
    - Miscellaneous "Q's", undated (Box 5, Folder 465)
    - Miscellaneous "R's", undated (Box 5, Folder 490)
    - Montgomery family, undated (Box 5, Folder 340)
    - Morehouse family, undated (Box 5, Folder 343)
    - Morgan family, undated; Covers the years 1620-1874. (Box 5, Folder 344)
    - Nash family, undated; Covers the years 1639-1884. (Box 5, Folder 347)
    - Nichols family, undated (Box 5, Folder 348)
    - Ogden family, undated; Covers the years 1840-1977. See also WHI, PM, Notices, Auction. (Box 5, Folder 350)
    - Olmstead family, undated; File 355 covers the years 1612-1983. File 356 covers the years 1650-1976. File 357 includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes. File 359 includes G. Evans Hubbard's notes. (Box 5, Folder 355, 356, 357, 358, 359)
    - Osborn family, undated (Box 5, Folder 360)
    - Ottavi family, undated (Box 5, Folder 362)
    - Pardee / Purdee family, undated; Includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes. (Box 5, Folder 402)
    - Partrick family, undated; Covers the years 1788-1947. (Box 5, Folder 410)
    - Patchen family, undated; Covers the years 1663-1779. (Box 5, Folder 420)
    - Phillips family, undated (Box 5, Folder 423)
    - Pierce / Pearce family, undated; Includes David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes. (Box 5, Folder 425)
    - Platt family, undated; Covers the years 1788-1806. (Box 5, Folder 430)
    - Pont family, undated (Box 5, Folder 435)
    - Post family, undated; Coverage begins from 1898. For Angeline Post, see WHI, Hurlbutt Street Schoolhouse records. (Box 5, Folder 437)
    - Price family, undated; Covers the years 1764-1909. (Box 5, Folder 440)
    - Randal / Randle / Randall family, undated; File 494 and File 496 include David Hermon Van Hoosear's book excerpt. (Box 5, Folder 493, 494, 496)
    - Raymond family, undated; Covers the years 1664-1973. For Laura Raymond, see WHI, Hurlbutt Street Schoolhouse records. (Box 5, Folder 500, 501)
    - Reed family, undated; Covers the years 1749-1878. (Box 5, Folder 505)
    - Resseguie family, undated; Covers the years 1704-1887. (Box 5, Folder 510)
    - Richards family, undated; Covers the years 1760-1924. (Box 5, Folder 520)
    - Richards family - Correspondence, 1875-1935 (Box 5, Folder 530)
    - Rockwell family, undated (Box 5, Folder 580)
    - Rogers family, undated (Box 5, Folder 581)
    - Rounds family, undated (Box 5, Folder 582)
    - Royal descent, undated (Box 5, Folder 585)
    - Rusco / Ruscoe family, undated (Box 5, Folder 590)
  - S - Z
    - Miscellaneous "S's", undated (Box 5, Folder 600)
    - Miscellaneous "V's", undated (Box 5, Folder 750)
    - Miscellaneous "W's", undated (Box 5, Folder 850)
    - Miscellaneous "Y's", undated (Box 5, Folder 990)
    - Miscellaneous “U’s”, undated (Box 5, Folder 740)
    - Sackman family, undated (Box 5, Folder 605)
    - Samuelson family, undated; See also WHI, PM, Samuelson. (Box 5, Folder 611b)